A Guide to the Sellers Family Papers, 1817-1852
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Sellers Family Papers, 1817-1852
The Library of Virginia
37822
22 pages
Sellers Family
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Purchased, 23 June 2000, from L and T Respess Books, Charlottesville, Virginia.
Biographical Information
The Sellers family resided in Augusta and Rockingham Counties, Virginia.
Scope and Content
Papers, 1817-1852, of the Sellers family of Augusta and Rockingham Counties, Virginia, consisting of estate accounts, receipts, promissory notes, deeds, notices, and a power of attorney.
Contents List
- Receipt, 19 September 1817, written to Daniel Sellers of Rockingham County for payment of a dower bequeathed to Mary Barbary, wife of John Pence.
- Promissory note, 7 March 1823, of Henry Pirkey (1772-1823) issued by Philip Pirkey. On the verso also includes receipt, 1835, for payment received of Isaac Sellers (1797-1839), administrator of the estate.
- Receipts, 1823 and 1852, for payment of Augusta County property taxes issued to Daniel Sellers.
- Receipt, 8 February 1830, written to Isaac Sellers by P. Williams for legal services provided for the Long estate.
- Receipt, March 1830, written to the estate of Reuben Long (1773-1830) by Abraham Strickler for his services as the estate's appraiser.
- Receipt, 23 March 1830, written to Isaac Sellers, administrator of Reuben Long's estate, by John Miller for payment for services as a cryer at Long's estate sale.
- Notice, 24 March 1830, issued by Joseph Strickler (1766-1841) that a debt owed by the Long estate to John Beaver is just. Also includes the receipt for payment made by Isaac Sellers to Beaver.
- Notice, 26 Aug. 1830, issued by Joseph Strickler that a debt owed by the Long estate to Benjamin Grigsby (b. 1795) is just.
- Notice, 30 Aug. 1830, issued by a Justice of the Peace that a debt owed to Dr. Thomas T. Blackford (1794-1863) by the estate of Reuben Long is just. On the verso is a receipt for payment received from Isaac Sellers.
- Deed, 3 March 1831, between William P. Poage (1781-1855) of Kentucky and Isaac Sellers for 83 acres in Augusta County. Also includes deed, 24 May 1831, between John Roberts and Isaac Sellers for 10 1/2 acres in Augusta County.
- Deed, March 1831, between William P. Poage of Kentucky and Isaac Sellers for 83 acres in Augusta County.
- Notice, 5 April 1831, issued by Abraham Strickler that a debt owed by Reuben Long's estate to George Dadisman (1790-1844) is just.
- Estate accounts, 1833-1837, of Michael Whitmore, administrator for Isaac Sellers.
- Power of attorney, 26 May 1834, granting Isaac Sellers the authority to act as agent for Elizabeth Swift and the estate of Margaret Runkle (1776-1834).
- Deed of indenture, 25 Feb. 1837, between David Rankin of Augusta County and Isaac Sellers and Henry Furrer for the exclusive rights and patent to a clover hulling machine.
- Receipt, 1846, for payment of Augusta County property taxes issued to Susan Sellers.
- Voucher, no date, of Reuben Long and one unidentified item.